Local 1199 Additional Records 5854
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Local 1199 Additional Records
1968-1990
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
National Union of Hospital and Nursing Home Employees (NUHHCE)
5854
8 cubic feet
8 linear ft.
Records (documents).
5713678
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, June 28, 2006
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 17, 2019
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5206: Local 1199 Records 5206-D: Local 1199 Drug Division Records 5206-G: Local 1199 Guild Division Records 5206-PR: Local 1199 President Leon Davis Records 5206-S: Local 1199 Executive Secretary Moe Foner Records 5206-X: Local 1199 Clippings and News Releases 5457: Mark Lillian Collection of Roosevelt Hospital (NYC) vs. Local 1199, 1962 Representational Dispute Documents 5510: Local 1199 Records 5520m: "Building a Union in the Hospitals: the Organization of Local 1199 at Montefoire Hospital, 1948-1958" Manuscript 5525: Local 1199 Additional Files 5651: Local 1199 Additional Records 5768: Sidney Cahn Collection of League of Voluntary Hospitals & Homes of New York vs. Local 1199 Drug and Hospital Union Arbitration Files 5680 OH: Local 1199 Oral History Project 5871: Local 1199 Additional Records 5929: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Records 5929 AV: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Audio-Visual Materials 5929 MB: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Memorabilia 5929 P: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Photographs 5933: Local 1199 Drug and Hospital Union News files 5933 P: Local 1199 Photograph Files 5938: Local 1199 Leon Davis Additional Papers 5945: Local 1199 Additional Records 5948: Local 1199 (Rochester, N.Y.) Records 5984 AV: Local 1199 Additional Videos 5984 AV: Local 1199 Additional Videos 6016: Local 1199 National Benefit and Pension Fund Records 6062: Paul Friedman Collection of National Union of Hospital and Health Care Employees, Local 1199 Miscellany 6069: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Additional Files 6084 G: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Women of Hope Poster Sets 6140: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project 6140 AV: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Audio Recordings 6140 P: Local 1199 Moe Foner Photographs 6169: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Files 6169 AV: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Audio-Visual Materials 6169 MB: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Memorabilia 6169: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Files
Health facilities -- Employees -- Labor unions -- New York (State); National Union of Hospital and Health Care Employees.; 1199, National Health and Human Service Employees Union.; AFSCME; National Union of Hospital and Health Care Employees. District 1199
5713678
- Founding Convention NUHHCE (National Union of Hospital and Health Care Employees) 11/29/73-12/1/73, 1973-1973 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Founding Conference-National Union of Hospital and Nursing Home Employees 12/12/69, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Report from the President on behalf of the officers of NUHHCE to the Delegates of the Second National Convention 12/10/75, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Report from the President on behalf of the officers of the NUHHCE to the delegates of the Second National Convention 12/10/75, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- NUHHCE Second Convention 12/10/75, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- NUHHCE Third Convention 12/13/75, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Third Convention NUHHCE Minutes, Committee Reports 11/16/77, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Third Convention NUHHCE Minutes, Committee Reports 11/16/77, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Fourth Convention NUHHCE -Wage Standards, Organizational Activities, and Officers Reports 12/79, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- NUHHCE Fifth Convention-Financial Report 12/25/81, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- NUHHCE Fifth Convention-Wage Standards and Organizational Reports, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- NUHHCE Seventh Convention Minutes 12/9-12/87, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Seventh Convention Contract and Financial Reports, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Area Memos State College-PGH, 1973-1985 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Area Memos State College-PGH, 1969-1972 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Area Memos-New England, 1978-1985 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Area Memos-Connecticut, 1969-1972 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Area Memos-Connecticut, 1973-1984 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Area Memos-Massachusetts, 1970-1979 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Area Memos-Maine, 1975-1980 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Area Memos-Rhode Island\, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Area Memos-Rhode Island\, 1973-1980 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Area Memos-Quad Cities, 1976-1985 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Area Memos-Indiana [folder 1 of 2], 1974-1985 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Scope and Contents
  11/5/74-3/4/85
- Area Memos-Indiana [folder 2 of 2], 1974-1985 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Area Memos-Binghamton, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Area Memos-Washington D.C., 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Area Memos-Washington D.C., 1973-1982 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Area Memos-Seattle, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Area Memos-Ohio [folder 1 of 2], 1978-1981 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Area Memos-Ohio [folder 2 of 2], 1978-1981 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Contract Language-Closure, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Contract Language-Grievance Procedure, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Contract Language-Low Patient Census, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Contract Language-Open Shop Contract, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Contract Language-Re-opener Language, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Contract Language-Staffing, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Contract Language-Sick Leave, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Contract Language-Strike Notice, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Contract Language-Sexual Harassment, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Contract Language-Subcontracting, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Contract Language-Successorship, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Contract Language-Temporary Employees, 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Contract Language-Unpaid Leave (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Contract Language-Vacation, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Canada-Health Care System (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Childcare, 1986-1988 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- CLUW (Coalition of Labor Union Women) Chapter Presidents, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Contract Department, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Contract Forms-Collective Bargaining Settlements (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Contract Settlement Forms (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Contract Forms-Distribution (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Contract Forms-Dropped Institutions (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Contract Forms-Easylink (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Contract Forms-Request for Strike Notice (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Cost Containment, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Court Decisions, 1983-1987 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Decertification, 1978-1981 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Contract Language, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Deinstitutionalization [folder 1 of 2], 1981-1983 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Deinstitutionalization [folder 2 of 2], 1981-1983 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Drugs [folder 1 of 2], 1983-1987 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Drugs [folder 2 of 2], 1983-1987 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- 1199 Elections [folder 1 of 2], 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- 1199 Elections [folder 2 of 2], 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Election Forms 1199M, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- ELSS (Electronic Legislative Search System) [folder 1 of 3], 1986 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- ELSS (Electronic Legislative Search System) [folder 2 of 3], 1986 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- ELSS (Electronic Legislative Search System) [folder 2 of 3], 1986 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Family Budget, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Federal Legislation, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- The Fight Back [folder 1 of 2], 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- The Fight Back [folder 2 of 2], 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Flexible Staffing, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- For-Profit Health Centers, 1983-1986 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- For-Profit Health Centers, 1983-1986 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- For-Profit Health Care, 1984-1987 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Forum, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Future Trends, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- George Meany Center, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Government Contracts, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Gramm-Rudman, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Health Care Costs, 1984-1987 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Health Insurance, 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Health Care Election Report, 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Health Policy Weekly, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Health Policy Weekly, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Health Policy Weekly, 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Health Policy Weekly, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Job Classifications, 1982-1985 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Kennedy-Stark Bill, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Labor, 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Labor Costs, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Labor Archives News, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  January 1986.
- Labor Management, 1985-1987 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Labor Trends, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Language Proposals, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Layoff-Bumping Seniority, 1984-1988 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Legal Cases, 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Legislative Outlook, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Library, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Library Acquisitions List, 1983-1985 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- LPNs (Licensed Practical Nurses) (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Long Term Care, 1985-1988 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Malpractice, 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Management, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Management Consultants, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Management Report, 1983-1986 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Medicaid, 1982-1986 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Medicare, 1983-1986 (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Medicare/Medicaid, 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Membership Report, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 34)
- Mental Health, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 35)
- Military Health Care, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 36)
- Mine Safety and Health Administration (MSHA), 1985 (Box 4, Folder 37)
- Micro-technology, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 38)
- Organizing Leaflets, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 39)
- Miscellaneous, 1983-1986 (Box 4, Folder 40)
- June 12, 1982. (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Legislation, 1983-1988 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Mini-Computers for Labor Conference, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  4/24-29/83
- NLRB Decisions, 1982-1984 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- NLRB, 1985-1987 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- National Labor Relations Board [folder 1 of 3], 1984-1988 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- National Labor Relations Board [folder 3 of 3], 1984-1988 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- National Labor Relations Board [folder 3 of 3], 1984-1988 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- NLRB Unfair Labor Practices, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- National Union-Arbitration Seminar, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  6/1-2/83
- National Union Organizing Status Report, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- National Union Conference on Negotiations, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- National Union Conference on Negotiations [folder 1 of 2], 1983 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  2/83
- National Union Conference on Negotiations [folder 2 of 2], 1983 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- National Union Delegate Election, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- National Union Districts/Areas Puerto Rico, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- National Union Executive Board District 1199 Massachusetts Report, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- New York Negotiations, 1968-1970 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Newspaper Clippings, 1969-1984 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- NLRB Election Report, 1983-1984 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- 1199E Negotiations, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- 1199J Negotiations, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- 1199J Negotiations, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Nursing Homes, 1986-1988 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Pay Rates in the Public Service, 1981-1982 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- SEIU, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Senate Bills, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Senior Citizens, 1985-1987 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Snub Survey, 1980-1981 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Shiftwork, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Snub Reference [folder 1 of 2], 1982 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Snub Reference [folder 2 of 2], 1982 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Social Security Withdrawals, 1982-1983 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Social Security Withdrawals-Memos [folder 1 of 2], 1982 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Social Security Withdrawals-Memos [folder 2 of 2], 1982 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Unfair Labor Practices, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Western Union, 1986-1989 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Women, 1985-1988 (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Executive Board, 1969-1970 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  September, March 1970 December 1969
- Executive Board, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  June, December 1971 Union Conference 12/10-11/71
- National Conference 1973 Executive Board (Box 7, Folder 3)
  Jan, July, Nov 1973
- Executive Board, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  7/12-13/73
- Founding Convention, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  11/28/73-12/1/73
- Executive Board, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  2/25/1974
- Executive Board, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  7/23/1974
- Executive Board, 1974-1975 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  5/15-17/75 & 12/74
- Executive Board, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  11/20-21/75
- Executive Board, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  12/14/1975
- Executive Board, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  5/6-7/76
- Executive Board, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  11/4-5/76
- Executive Board, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  5/19/1978
- Executive Board, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  5/5-6/77
- Executive Board, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  10/13-14/77
- Executive Board, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  Oct-78
- Executive Board, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  5/17-18/79
- Executive Board, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  11/9/1979
- Fourth Convention [folder 1 of 2], 1979 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  12/79 Minutes and Reports
- Fourth Convention [folder 2 of 2], 1979 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Executive Board, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Executive Board [folder 1 of 3], 1981 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Executive Board [folder 2 of 3], 1981 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Executive Board [folder 3 of 3], 1981 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Executive Board, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  January 25,1982
- Executive Board, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  8-Apr-82
- Executive Board, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  17-Oct-82
- Executive Board, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  June and July 1983
- Executive Board, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  21-Nov-83
- Executive Board, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  1983
- Executive Board, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  January, February, March 1984
- Executive Board, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  April, May, June 1984
- Executive Board, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  8/6/1984
- Executive Board, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  2/5-6/85
- Administrative Committee, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  1/11/1985